Uh, hey guys. Uh, I just I just want to
say um thank you to the Will family and
Coach Ko and Coach Flow and Coach Nilson
believing in me and trusting um, you
know, in my in my abilities to come out
there and and be able to um, you know,
perform um, and give them my all every
single day. So, I just want to say thank
you to the whole organization and um,
guys are getting getting someone special
oneonone.
>> Awesome. Lindsay, go ahead and kick
things off and then we'll just follow
the the chat. Alec, Kevin,
>> hey Caleb. Um, welcome to Minnesota.
Congratulations. Just just wondering if
you can walk us through a little bit of
what tonight was like for you. Kind of,
you know, who you were who you were
spending the evening with and and what
was it like to get that call and share
that moment with your family.
>> Yeah. Uh it was great. Um the whole day
was nerve-wracking if I'm being honest.
Uh kind of had the jitters the whole
entire day. Um I was hoping that it was
the Vikings. Um I was kind of like just
talking to my family like I really hope
it's them. um because I I loved
everything that I seen when I went there
from the people to the to the players
and the coaches and um just the whole
atmosphere around in Minnesota. So, um
it it was pretty fun. Um but around the
time when I got the call, uh I seen it
and I seen like Vikings and I like
jumped and I looked at my brother, he
was like, "You could answer." And I'm
like, "All right." I picked it up and
then um history was there. Uh the family
was there. It was great. Um it's a
blessing honestly. I'm I'm just happy.
I'm just happy that uh that I'm here in
this situation. I'm blessed.
>> Hey. Hey, uh Caleb, congrats, man. Um
Kevin O'Connell said that Ryan Nielsen,
the Dline coach, went down there and I
think spent some time with with you.
What was that like? What did you take
from that? What stood out from kind of
that interaction?
>> Yeah. Uh it was great. Uh coach came
down there and talked to me. Uh had me
get on the board, uh see my abilities,
see what I known and what I could um you
know, develop at. Um, we had great
conversation. We talked we talked it up
a lot. Uh, went and got lunch. Um,
really just enjoyed each other's time.
It was kind of like, you know what I
mean, just getting getting to know each
other. Um, I enjoyed it a lot, you know
what I mean? Um, he was the first coach
to come see me throughout the whole
process. So, um, you know, it meant a
lot to me and um, I kind of knew from
there a little bit like, you know, this
is definitely going to be home for me.
>> Caleb, where are you at healthwise with
your foot? I'm sure teams were asking
you about that and you were and I'm sure
there was a process of you trying to
convince, you know, and talk to teams
about it. Where are you at with it and
and what do you expect, you know, going
forward?
>> Yeah. Um, so at the moment right now,
um, just taking it one day at a time,
you know what I mean? I'm getting
better, getting healthy, um, so I can go
out there and perform, um, when that
time come. Um, so I'm feeling good.
Feeling great. Just got a CT scan. CT
went well. Uh, so every everything's
everything's everything's going forward.
Good going forward.
Yeah, Caleb, on those lines, it sounded
like that foot injury popped up before
the season or in the early on in the
season, you tried to play through it.
Just why did you try to do that? What
led into your decision to try to gut
through that as opposed to shutting it
down and and kind of preserving your
draft stock?
>> Um, if I'm being honest, man, I'm not
the type of guy to shut anything down,
you know what I mean? Like, uh, I want
to be out there with my brothers and I
want to play the game of football. I
love the game. Um, I love everything
that comes with it. Uh, from the work to
the to the long nights to early
mornings, like the hard work in the
weight room. like I love it all. Um so
nothing in my mind was telling me like
shut it down, you know what I mean? Um I
knew it was broken in the second quarter
against LSU. Went in there, got a shot
in my foot, didn't work, still went out
there. Um and then it completely broke
through. Um but I was fighting, you know
what I mean? And um fought in this in
the combine as well. Um I'm competitive
as hell. So that's that's just me.
That's the type of guy I am. Although I
didn't mean I didn't mean to cuss, but
in that mode a little bit, but um that's
just the type of guy I am. So um yeah.
>> Well, and just to follow up quick, that
that first operation that sound like
that didn't fix everything. Correct. So,
was the second one just to come through
and clean something up or did you have
the same break the second time? Like
what happened?
>> Uh, just a little freak accident. Um,
kind of just something that I I really
couldn't control. Um, so, you know,
control what I can control. Um, got it
repaired, got it fixed. Um, then, you
know, we're off to the races.
I'm wondering um so much of this process
is others evaluating you, but if you
gave us your own scouting report, uh
what are your strengths? Where are you
still looking to improve? Can you
describe Caleb Banks on the field?
>> Yeah. Uh somebody who's competitive,
hard worker, somebody's going to get
after it, uh somebody's going to get
after that quarterback and um get in
that back field to make plays. Um,
sometimes it might be a little
inconsistency on tape. Um, but I mean,
you know, you get under a good coach and
and a good uh staff and a good team and
good teammates, great teammates, like
you you going to want to go hard every
single play for them boys. So, um,
that's that's pretty much me. Um,
athletic to oneonone. Um,
did I say competitive? That's me. I'm
I'm I'm gonna talk I'm gonna talk smack
all day long. Uh, hard worker. I can go
on and on. I'm probably gonna say the
same thing, but that's just that's just
me though. I would say my strengths
though. My strengths. Um, you did ask
about that. My strengths. I would say
the run game, pass game. Um, kind of
just I feel like I haven't reached my
full potential yet though. I feel like I
got a lot to learn. Um, and I think I'm
going to learn a lot under coach
Nielson. I think he gonna help me
develop and coach FL as well. Um, I
think those guys are going to help me be
great. I'm doing I'm doing medium. I'm
sorry. Sorry. My mom came in. She looks
sad. Um, um, and I say my weaknesses. Uh
really just using my not not usually
using my hands. I feel like my technique
sometimes just goes out the window a
little bit. Um and I think that's
something I definitely could develop on.
Um you know having my eyes in the right
you guys hear me? I'm sorry. Somebody
was calling me. You guys hear me? Okay.
Yeah. Uh just having my eyes in the
right gap. Um and just you know playing
with my hands, you know. Um that's
pretty much it. Technique definitely
something I can develop on for sure.
Everything honestly if you ask me. Kell,
I know you mentioned um Coach Nielsson
and and Coach Flo. Just specifically
with Coach Flores, what are you excited
about, you know, working with him and
the way that he can use you in his
schemes?
>> Um, so when I went on the 30 visit, uh,
I remember he he sat us all he sat all
the players down and he said, um, I'm
just telling y'all right now, if we pick
you, like I'm going I'm going we going
to get after it. Like that's just like
first thing he said and I was like, oh
yeah, like I'm I'm all for that, you
know what I mean? And I and I and I love
it, you know what I mean? Um, and and
the scheme wise, you know what I mean?
defensive end, playing the big end. Uh,
so fourey kind of around there, three
technique, five technique. Um, kind of
just being be being able to use my
abilities. Um, I feel like I'm a freak
athlete. I'm oneonone. Um, not a lot of
guys have the skill set that I have, but
I feel like if I develop my tools, uh,
the way that I know I could, um, I could
be I could be dangerous if you ask me.
>> Hi, Caleb. kind of keeping with Flo,
just was there any feedback that he gave
you about where he would want to see you
grow and where he would maybe help you
develop at the next level?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> honestly, everything from my technique.
Um, I'm kind of echoing. I can hear
myself echoing a little bit. Um, my
technique, um, just, you know, just use
my hands, like I said, um, my eyes. Um,
getting better as a player, growing as a
person. Um, we talked, but we didn't
talk like, you know, crazy a lot, but,
um, with the conversations that we had,
it was good. Um, so,
>> hey, Caleb, just had one more. Um, what
happened at the combine like with the
foot at the combine? Like, I don't even
how did that play out? What happened?
And then, I mean, you've talked about
the decision to to play through it, work
out through it, but what happened?
>> Um, um, so that night before, um, it was
kind of like a freak accident. I was
practicing my starts. uh had on some
little skill cleat, some cleat I
shouldn't have had on running that 40
in, you know, 330 pounds, you know,
that's kind of it's kind of funky
wearing those, but um yeah, know the
foot just popped. It popped on me. Um on
my second rep of my start, um I'm
thinking it's a muscle problem, so I'm
not really thinking too much of it. Um
that next morning, I woke up, foot
wasn't swollen, foot wasn't, you know,
feeling weird or anything like that.
Walking on it, doing everything the
right way. Uh went out there on the
field. Um was practicing my starts,
warming up, I did the JBR jump, I did
the bird jump. um kind of a little pain
there, but it wasn't too bad. Um but
when I ran my 40, it was kind of it was
kind of bad, you know what I mean? Like
I was feeling it. Um ran a second 40
because I was trying to run faster in
pain, but I you know, I fought through
it. Um I pushed through it. Um
unfortunately, I didn't get the time
that I wanted, but um I feel like I
still went out there and performed the
best that I could. Um tried to do one
drill on the field, didn't really work
the way I wanted it to. Didn't feel
good. So, I decided to sit down because
it would have just, you know what I I
didn't want to put anything on tape
where it would have, you know, it would
have um been detrimental for me. So, um
and I wasn't myself. So, I just decided
to sit down. Um thought it was I thought
it was a cleat issue. So, that wouldn't
lie. I know everybody was saying like
it's a cleat. He said it was a cle was a
cleat. I really didn't know it was broke
at the time. So, um
>> yeah, that was that. But, yeah, it's
kind of crazy.
>> And then you you mentioned your mom who
walked in. Can you just describe how
much she's meant to you throughout this
journey?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Uh she's meant a lot. Uh that's
like that's my rock right there, man. Um
she's always there um helping me um you
know develop as a player, as a person.
Um and yeah, she's she's there on the
field too, guys. Like she she's she's
all in. Yeah. So um she she's done a
lot. Um and I'm happy that she's right
there on my side. Um I really wouldn't
have done none of this without her,
without her support. Um and I'm glad
that she's here supporting me every step
of the way. I know you guys seen her on
TV. She's doing a little dance. Um but
yeah, no, she's she's enjoying it. She's
really happy for me.
>> Ben, we'll round out with you.
>> Okay. Yeah. Caleb, I was just curious
what kind of advice they've given you uh
long term in terms of managing your
foot. If doctor talked to you about
weight, bringing that down and all, is
that something that would help or what
kinds of advice have they given you in
terms of how to handle your foot and
make sure this doesn't happen again?
>> Yeah. Uh so just taking care of my body
every single day. Um they talk to me
about that a lot. Um the weight, uh so
probably just losing I wanted to
personally lose 10 pounds. Um so be
around like 320 uh 315 around there. Uh,
that's just my personal preference. Um,
um, cleat. Cleat is a big thing. So, I
talked to the EQ staff. They they was
real big on that. They told me they was
going to make sure everything was set.
Make sure I was in the right cleat. Make
sure I had the um, the fitting, the
soles, everything the right way so I can
go out there and perform um, so I can be
the best version that I could be.
>> Awesome. Caleb, thank you so much for
your time tonight. Congratulations.
>> Thank you so much. You guys have a great
one.